Dark secrets revealed.
Harry Potter and the Half-Blood Prince is a adventure,
fantasy film directed by David Yates.
As Lord Voldemort tightens his grip on both the Muggle and
wizarding worlds, Hogwarts is no longer a safe haven.
Harry suspects perils may even lie within the castle, but Dumbledore is more
intent upon preparing him for the final battle fast approaching.
Together they work to find the key to unlock Voldemorts defenses and to this end, Dumbledore recruits
his old friend and colleague Horace Slughorn, whom he believes holds crucial information.
Even as the decisive showdown looms, romance blossoms for
Harry, Ron, Hermione and their classmates.
Love is in the air, but danger lies ahead and
Hogwarts may never be the same again.
Harry Potter, played by Daniel Radcliffe.
Ron Weasley, played by Rupert Grint.
Hermione Granger, played by Emma Watson.
Horace Slughorn, played by Jim Broadbent.
Albus Dumbledore, played by Michael Gambon.
Draco Malfoy, played by Tom Felton.
Harry Potter and the Half-Blood Prince is a 2009 fantasy film
directed by David Yates from a screenplay by Steve Kloves.
It is based on the 2005 novel Harry Potter and the Half-Blood Prince by J.
It is the sequel to Harry Potter and the Order of the Phoenix (2007) and
the sixth instalment in the Harry Potter film series.
It stars Daniel Radcliffe as Harry Potter, alongside Rupert Grint and Emma Watson as
Harry's best friends Ron Weasley and Hermione Granger respectively.
The story follows Harry's sixth year at Hogwarts as he receives a mysterious textbook, falls in love,
and attempts to retrieve a memory that holds the key to Lord Voldemort's downfall.
Filming began on 24 September 2007, leading to the film's
worldwide cinematic release on 15 July 2009.
With an estimated budget of $250 million, it is one of the most expensive films ever
made and the most expensive film in the Harry Potter film series.
Harry Potter and the Half-Blood Prince was released in 2D cinemas and IMAX formats in
the United Kingdom and United States on 15 July 2009, by Warner Bros.
It received positive reviews from critics, with praise for the visual effects, character
development, performances, darker tone, and faithfulness to the source material.
The film was a major box office success, grossing $941 million
worldwide, making it the second-highest-grossing film of 2009.
It also grossed $394 million worldwide during its opening, which made
it the highest worldwide five-day opening at the time.
The film was nominated for many awards, including the Academy Award for Best Cinematography
and the BAFTA Award for Best Production Design and Best Special Visual Effects.
It was followed by Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows – Part 1 in 2010.
The film explores themes of witch, dying and death,
london, england, magic, school of witchcraft.